Let us discuss about the mission, the meta-spitable.
So basically, meta-spitable is one of the test-tenware-on-ment.
Let me show you here, yeah, it's a secure place to perform the penetration testing and security
research.
So, this machine is used to attack and practice multiple techniques.
So, even Malal badyaz is one of the penetration testing scanning the server.
So, this machine will be act like a server and this will give, this will think like a server
and what we can do, we can practice the attack, basically we can practice the attack and
we can instead of directly attacking any one organization server.
So, we can utilize this meta-spitable Linux, so this will act like a server and we can
practice our security research and security exploitation.
So, that's why I have installed the meta-spitable mission in my course, I have involved.
But the practicing was very, very less one or two videos, we just practiced and attacked
the other attacks that us covered are really in a Windows machine.
The most of the commands, not only most every commands and every tools that was discussed
in this course is used by the attackers, is used by attackers previously and even now also.
So, most of the exploitation tools and exploitation script, even the developed code that
was used by the attackers and the extender the code into the next format for an antivirus
evasions and I passing the EDRs.
So, you already seen all the topics, how we made this course perfectly, right.
So, now the meta-spitable Linux was download or successfully, let's install this one, let's
find out where this, where it is, let's double click on this, so we can to it in another
way, let's close the other tabs, okay, it's good to this one, name it as meta, YOS image
we don't have an IS image and it's a Linux machine, so let me select Linux, low Linux and
let me do like 2GB of RAM and CPU was 2 and you existing visual disk, so what I did,
I just came to the hard disk and I had given you an existing visual disk file, so I just
given this at go to the meta-spitable Linux, open choose this finish and good to go, so let
me close all the machines, all the other machines, now the meta-spitable machine was booting
up, okay try booting up and away pick option, let's resolve this error first, let's close
this machine or off this one and once you start the machine, press escape, okay, so once
the machine has been started, press escape key, okay escape, okay, again it went, let's
press now, yeah, now it went to the kernel, let's give it to edit, redirect to kernel,
okay, you can use a pan down for navigate to, navigate to a pan down, okay, so for edit
option you need to give e, go to the kernel and ue, okay, so let's give no epic, and
now let's start this, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay,
I show my e-board not responding, again in the kernel I am restarting, so give me a sec, let's
escape, now give me that, all you guys are speaking your time, yeah, now we got, let's
give e, and e, no epic, and b to boot, yeah, now it was booted, okay, so I just given,
I just edited the kernel as no epic, and the navigator to root, and I given b, so to boot,
okay, so that's the one, I have did, so now you can see meta spreader machine has successfully
turned on, and as self admin, yeah, if I do, if config, so here you can see the IP address,
so this machine is optional to install, so you don't need to install, if it, if you do
not have enough memory space in your machine, so this is really optional, but we need
a Windows, as well as the Kali Linux machine, okay, also, let me, let me tell you, let
me once more I will tell you what I did, okay, so once you start the machine, give escape
button, okay, you escape button, press escape button continuously, okay, now it, it went
to the 8.4 kernel, u, e, you edit, go to the kernel, e to edit, okay, and type no ap,
ic, no epic, okay, and you enter, so now you can see I was navigating up to the root, and
I am pressing b, so b will be the boot, plus b to boot, right, so b will be the boot, so
now you can see the machine has been started, and it was running in the backend, so this
is how I is troubleshooter that no epic problem, okay, so we need to do one more thing,
in every machine you have installed, go to the settings, and go to the network, change
this to bridge adapter, okay, go to settings, and change the network to bridge adapter,
go to settings, change this to bridge adapter, okay, every machine needs to be in a bridge
adapter, okay, cool, thanks guys for watching this video, we will hop off from here and
We will continue our discussion in the next section, bye bye.